嗨，大家好，我是TheCherno，欢迎回到我的游戏引擎系列，所以上期，我们讨论了相机
hey, what's up guys, my name is TheCherno, welcome back to my game engine series, so last time, we talked about cameras
我们创建了一期相机板书的视频，如果你们还没有看过那期的话，一定要去看看哦
and we created an autograph camera, definitely check out that video, if you haven't already
今天，在这周中期的特别节目中，我们实际上将把大量代码转移到实际的Sandbox程序中
and today, in this special mid week episode, we're actually going to be moving a lot of our code into the actual Sandbox application
我将向你们展示一些技巧，告诉你们如何以一种更好的方式设置它
and I'll show you guys a few tricks with how you can kind of set that up in a bit of a better way
所以我决定把这一期改成一周中的一期，只是因为它看起来像是一个小变化
so I decided to make this a mid week episode, just because it's like kind of like a minor change
我们并没有真正学到什么新东西，那就是重构代码和搬来搬去
we're not really learning anything new, which is refactoring code and moving in around
所以我认为，如果我像往常一样在周日制作一期新视频，对你们不公平
and so I didn't think it would be fair to you guys, if I just kind of made a new video on like Sunday as usual
然后就是这个重大的失望，居然不是那样，太失望了
and then it's just like this major disappointment, not that, this is gonna be a major disappointment
顺便说一句，你们肯定还是应该看看这期视频
you should definitely still watch this video by the way
但让我知道你们对周中期视频的总体看法，我们将继续讨论Hazel
but let me know what you think about mid week episodes in general as we kind of move on with Hazel
我们开始做越来越多的事情，而且变得更加令人兴奋，我可能会考虑一周做两期
and we start doing more and more stuff, and it gets more exciting, I might consider doing two episodes a week
所以，直接去评论吧，让我知道你们的想法，我可能会在以后那样做
so just drop a comment, and let me know what you think about that, and I might do that in the future
patreon.com/theCherno是支持的最好方式，感谢所有让这系列成为可能的人
patreon.com/TheCherno is the best way to support this series, thank you to everyone who made this series possible
如果你们继续在那里帮助支持该系列，你们将可以访问我的私人开发仓库Hazel
if you go ahead and help support the series there, you'll get access to my private development repository of Hazel
我希望我们有比所有这些东西更多的最后代码，嗯，然后你们也可以早点收到视频
I wish we've got much more of last code than all this stuff, um and then you also get videos early
就像你们可以访问一个关于Discord的私人频道，在那里我们可以更详细地谈论这些事情
and like you can get access to a private channel on Discord, where we kind of talk about these things in more detail
你们可以基本上帮助计划这些视频，真的很酷，好了，所以让我们重构一下我们的代码
and you can kind of just um, essentially help plan these videos, which is really cool, um okay, so let's refact to our code
那么上期我们有了整个相机系统，位置，旋转
so last time we had this whole camera system, position, rotation
我还给了你们一些作业，看看你们是否能让相机对用户的输入做出反应
I also gave you guys some homework to actually see if you could make the camera respond to user input
我们今天也会实现那个，那将是今天视频中有趣的部分
and we'll actually do that today as well, that's gonna be the fun part of today's today's video
但我们首先需要做的是，我显然不太喜欢在Application内的这些东西
but what we need to do first of all is, I don't like that this stuff obviously is inside Application
我们有个SandboxApp，如果我们看这里，它是个实际的独立应用，这是我们的exe文件
we have a SandboxApp, if we look over here, it's an actual separate application, this is our exe file
在这一点上，Hazel只是一个静态库，这个SandboxApp是一切都应该存在的地方
Hazel is just a static library at this point, this SandboxApp is where everything should exist
让我们讨论一下如何做到这一点，因为这个ExampleLayer，我们在这里有这个Sandbox
so let's talk about how we can do that, because this example layer, this kind of Sandbox that we have here
这个例子基本上就是我们的游戏，对吧，它可能只是一个3D应用程序，不一定是游戏
this example that is our game essentially, right, and it could be like just a 3D application, doesn't have to be a game
但在这种情况下，这只是我们的一种应用程序，对吧，这是我们的实际应用
but in this case, it's just this is kind of our app, right, this is our actual application
所以这就是特定于该应用程序的所有代码所在的位置
so this is where all of the code that is specific to this application should be
我想要做的第一件事就是把这些东西清理一下，我们有类似于ExampleLayer的东西，很好
first thing I want to do is clear all this stuff up, we have like example layer, which is fine
我们有OnUpdate，它目前只是像输入轮询一样测试，所以我们可以去掉那个
we have OnUpdate, which at the moment just tests out like input polling, so we can get rid of that um
我们还有一个测试ImGuiRender，我们也不需要它了
we also have a test, ImGuiRender, which we don't need either amount
然后我们有一个OnEvent，当我们按下某个键或其他键时，就像你们知道的那样
and then we've got an OnEvent, when we press a certain key or whatever, it like just you know
这是一种对事件的响应，对输入事件的响应，而不是轮询
this is the kind of responding to event, um to input events rather than polling
所以我们可以去掉所有的代码，因为我们不需要那些
so we can get rid of all that code, because we don't need any of that um
现在它将进入Applicatioin，并开始带一些参数
now it's going to enter application, and start carrying the stuff across
所以这个while循环实际上就是我们所需要的，所以我就把这些都剪掉
so this while running loop is actually kind of what we need, so I'll just cut this all
我将把这些内容留在这里，基本上就是层更新和ImGui更新
and I'll leave this stuff here, which is basically just layer updating and also ImGui updating
这就是主要的游戏循环，我猜是应用循环，然后在这，把这个放到OnUpdate中
um this is our main kind of game loop I guess our Application loop, and then over here, I'll just put this into OnUpdate
现在这不会立即起作用，我们必须重新编写一些代码才能使其运行起来
now this isn't gonna immediately work, and we'll have to refact us some code to make it work
接下来，我将向该ExampleLayer中添加一些私有成员
so let's go ahead and do that, I'm gonna add some private members into this ExampleLayer
如果我们返回到Application，它基本上将是我们使用的所有内容
if we go back to Application, it's basically gonna be everything that we used
所以我们有所有共享指针的东西，我们有相机，我想可能就是那样了
so we had all this shared pointer stuff, we had the camera, I think that's probably it
所以着色器和顶点数组，我将回到这里，我们将把它作为私有字段添加到SandboxApp
so the shader and the vertex array, I'll go back here, and we'll add this into our SandboxApp over here as just private fields
现在我们需要一些东西来清理这一切，嗯，Hazel应该有我们需要的一切
now we're gonna need some stuff to clean this up, um Hazel should have everything we need
虽然我们已经很久没有添加到Hazel中了，所以我们肯定需要扩展一下
we haven't added stuff to Hazel in ages though, so we definitely need to kind of expand that
我们在渲染器中什么也没有找到，正如你们所看到的，这里是这里，所以让我们先清理一下
we find nothing in the Renderer, as you can see is here is here, so let's just clean that up
所以我们需要Hazel/Renderer，让我们看看这里有什么，我们真的需要所有这些东西
so we need to have um Hazel Renderer, let's see what's in here, we need to have all of this stuff really
所以我们可以包含Renderer，RenderCommand，再次记住，有些东西将包含其他东西
so we could have Renderer, we can have like RenderCommand, and again remember some things will include other things
例如RenderCommand包含RendererAPI，对吧，它包含了VertexArray
like for example RenderCommand includes RendererAPI, right, which includes VertexArray
所以你们不必真的把所有东西都放在这里，但无论如何这也是一个很好的练习
so you don't have to actually put everything in here, but it's good practice too anyway
因为如果我突然从渲染器中删除和包含，其他所有东西都依赖，对吧
because if I suddenly remove and include from Renderer, that everything else relied on, right
我将不得不在其他地方手动添加它来破解我的代码，我不想那样
I'm gonna have to include it manually somewhere else gonna break my code, I don't want that
所以这是个很好的实践，基本上说，我希望在实际的HazelAPI中的所有东西都是公开的
so it's pretty good practice, to say basically that everything that I definitely know I want in the actual HazelAPI to be kind of public
好了，这些东西应该包含在这里，我是按照Norris的特定顺序来做的，真的不是太重要
right, um that stuff should be included here, and I'm doing this in Norris specific order, it doesn't really matter too much
但我用的是OrthographicCamera
but I'm doing with OrthographicCamera
渲染程序中的几乎所有接口都应该暴露，RendererAPI不需要
pretty much everything in that Renderer thing should be expose, RendererAPI doesn't need to be
所以我不会在这里添加它，但我认为其他所有东西，你们知道，应该是图形上下文也不需要
so I'm not gonna add it there, um but everything else I think, you know, should be graphics context doesn't need to be either
请记住，那并不意味着，因为它们没有在这里列出，它们是私人的，显然它们不是
um keep in mind, that doesn't mean that, because they're not listed here that they're private, obviously they're not
如果你们知道的其他东西，比如Renender包含RenderCommand，它包含RendererAPI
um if something else you know like Renderer includes RenderCommand, which includes RendererAPI
所以RendererAPI实际上是可访问的，只是没有在这里明确列出，仅此而已
so RendererAPI is actually accessible, it's just not listed here explicitly, that's all
因为实际上并不需要使用它
because it's not really needed to be used
所以我可能会做一些，我可能会把所有的资源放在这里
so I might just do some, I might just put all the kind of resources down here
让我们看看，这样我们就可以有基于Renderer和RenderCommand的渲染工具
um let's see, so we can have Renderer and RenderCommand based render stuff
然后可能像Buffer、Shader和VertexArray的资源
and then maybe like um resources like buffer shader of VertexArray
然后就像这里的其他类型的渲染器基元一样，对吧，所以我们开始，这里有一些东西
and then like other kind of Renderer primitives here, right, so we kind of begin to um have some stuff here
如果我们想的话，我们可以在这里放一个小分隔符，让我们知道
and we could put like a little divided here if we wanted to that just kind of let us know that
这是与渲染器相关的东西，好了，我想我们还需要两个点，也许再多一个
this is Renderer related things, okay, and I think we need two more dots, maybe one more
这有点难说，好了，很好，酷，我们开始了，我们有我们的渲染器东西，漂亮
it's kind of hard to tell, yep okay, good, cool, so there we go, we've got our Renderer stuff, beautiful
因此，现在我们需要确保我们位于Hazel命名空间中
so now we need to actually make sure that we're in the Hazel namespace
现在我可以只使用namesapce Hazel，我不想这样做
now I could just using namespace Hazel, I don't want to
因为这只是一个例子，我真的想说明这个例子实际使用了什么
because this is an example and I want to really kind of just make that point of what is actually used by the example
好了，那么哪些是来自Hazel的，哪些不是，目前我们只是在这里找到共享指针
right, so what is from Hazel and what isn't, and currently we just have shared points to find here
我想在未来我们会为共享指针创建一个新的我们可以使用它的名称
I think in the future we are going to actually uh create a new name for shared pointers that we can use
但那将是另一期视频，我们稍后会讨论，所以这也将是一个Hazel的构造
um but that's gonna be another video, we'll talk about that later, so this will also be like a Hazel construct
因为在以后，我们可能还希望将其更改为其他名称
because in the future, we also might want to change it to something else
因为我们不想依赖于这个内存管理，对吧
because we don't want to kind of rely on this is for memory management um necessarily, right
好了，OrthographicCamera也是Hazel的，这个东西是Hazel的，这个也是，好了，太棒了
okay, OrthographicCamera is also Hazel, this stuff is Hazel, and so is that, okay, brilliant
所以现在我们需要在Application中实际创建一些东西
so now we need to actually create some of the stuff back in Application
我要复制相机，对吧，拿着它，把它剪下来，放在这里，好了
I'm gonna steal camera, right, just gonna take that, and cut it, and put it here, all right
然后，这个VertexArray.reset，以及我们这里的几乎所有东西
and then um this VertexArray.reset, and just pretty much everything that we have here
我们所有的着色器，我要把它剪掉，这样我们的Application构造就会变得如此简单，对吧
all of our shaders all that stuff, I'm gonna cut it um, so that our Application constructor goes down to just being as simple as this, right
我要把它粘贴到，现在有几个地方你们可以把这个放进去
um and I'm going to paste it into, now there's a few places you could put this in
你们可以看到，我们有SandBox构造，只执行了PushLayer，对吧
um you can see that, we have the Sandbox constructor, which does PushLayer, right
然后Push Layer实际上创建了新的ExampleLayer，并在这运行这段代码，但如果尝试那样做
and then push layer actually does new example layer, and runs this code here, however if we try and do that
你们可能会发现它实际上不起作用，原因是实际发生的情况是这是Application，对吧
you might find that it does actually doesn't work, and the reason is what actually happens is this is Application, right
Application构造函数，实际上不，它应该可以运行的
Application constructor, well actually no, it should work
因为Application构造函数创建窗口并执行所有这些操作，并且仅在完成之后
because the Application constructor creates the window and does all of that stuff, and only after that's done
因为这是一个默认的构造函数，所以基本上它将被称为
because this is a default constructor, so basically it will be called um
你们知道基本上是那样的，对吧，就在我们把这一层推入这个之前
you know like that essentially, right, just first before we push this layer in um
它实际上应该在上下文中创建我们的渲染器
it should actually create our Renderer in context and everything
因此，如果我们希望在构造函数中执行所有操作，那么应该是安全的
so it should be safe to do everything in the constructor if we wanted to
如果不是，那么你们始终可以创建类似于装饰函数
if it's not, then you can always create like an ornament function
那肯定是在，你们知道的，一些东西基本上已经初始化之后发生的
that definitely happens after you know stuff has been initialized basically
所以，我所说的东西已经被初始化了，我的意思是特别像图形渲染上下文
so and by stuff has been initialized I mean specifically like the graphics rendering context
因为在我们没有上下文之前，我们显然不能创建所有这些渲染器资源
because we obviously can't create like all of these renderer resources before we have a context
好了，再来一次，我可以使用namespace，但我不想
okay, so just bring the Hazel here again, I could use the namespace, but I don't want to
因为我想非常明确地说明什么是Hazel，什么不是，好了，然后我们有着色器
because I want to be really explicit about what is Hazel and what isn't, um okay, and then we have shader
因为你们可以看到，就像这种给我们带来的清晰度，我们可以看到所有最长的Hazel
because you can see, like the clarity that this kind of gives us, right, we can see everything the longest Hazel
好了，我认为这差不多就是那样了，让我们看看我们的代码，我认为我们没有其他东西
okay, and I think that's pretty much it, let's look over here in our code, I don't think we have anything else really
所以我认为那应该是可行的，让我们试着运行这段代码，看看会发生什么
so that should just work I think, let's just try and run this code and see what happens
好了，你们可以看到，运行的代码给我们的结果与我们在上期视频中得到的结果相同
okay, so you can see, that running, that code gives us the same result as we had in the previous video
所以我们已经成功地重构了所有内容，并将其移到SandboxApp类中，那真的很容易做到
so we've successfully refacted everything and moved it into the SandboxApp class, that was really easy to do
现在让我们继续下去，看看我们是否可以添加一些类似箭头键的输入或其他东西
now let's go ahead and see if we can add some kind of like arrow key input or something
使我们的相机能够移动，对吧
to just make our camera able to move, right
那么为了实现那个，让我们进入OnEvent，并响应某些事件
so to do that, let's come over here into OnEvent, and react to certain events
因此，这将是事件调度程序系统的一个很好的示例
so this is going to be a really good example of the event dispatcher system
所以如果我们打开Event文件，我们可以看到我们有这个EventDispatcher
so if we open up the event file, we can see we have this EventDispatcher
它能够调度某些类型的事件
which is capable of dispatching certain types of events
因此，我们将通过创建EventDispatcher和基本的实例来使用它
so we're gonna use that by creating the EventDispatcher and basically Disney an instance
Dispatcher的堆栈实例，dispatcher，它将接受event，然后就是dispatcher.Dispatch()
a stack instance of the dispatcher, right, dispatcher, which is going to take in the event, and then we'll see dispatcher.Dispatch()
然后是事件的类型，所以这将是一个Hazel::KeyPressedEvent，对吧
and then the type of event, so this is going to be a Hazel::KeyPressedEvent, right
我们将使用，我认为内部，它在哪里，可能在Core.h
and we're going to use the, I think inside, where is it, inside core maybe
我们有这个HZ_BIND_EVENT_FN，这就是我们想要使用的，对吧
we have this HZ_BIND_EVENT_FN, which is what we kind of want to use, right
所以这个HZ_BIND_EVENT_FN，然后会在这里给它一个函数，所以就是OnKeyPressedEvent
so this HZ_BIND_EVENT_FN and then we're gonna give it a function here, so we'll see OnKeyPressedEvent
这将是Hazel::KeyPressedEvent，那么这是什么，ExampleLayer::OnKeyPressedEvent
and it's gonna be Hazel::KeyPressedEvent events, so what is this, ExampleLayer::OnKeyPressedEvent
我认为就是那样，那就是所有的宏定义需求，很好，所以我们就把它放进去
I think that's it, that's all the macro needs yep, great, so we just put that in
现在如果它遇到其中一个，这就是，让我们看看为什么不起作用
and now if it encounters one of these, and this is, so let's see why that's not working
这与返回bool的事件函数有什么关系
what does this spatch one an event function, which is functioned returns bool
好了，所以这是一个空的，确保我们返回bool，好了，那个错误消失了，很好
okay, so yeah this is a void, make sure we're returning bool, okay, and yep that error goes away, great
Bool是指我们是否希望它是，比如阻塞，因为如果你们查看Application
so bool is whether or not we want it to like block, so because if you look at Application
你们可以看到发生的事情是，我们会仔细检查每一层，并调度事件
um you can see that what happens is that uh, we'll go through every layer and dispatch the event
但是，如果它已经被处理，那么我们中断，所以我们停止调度
however if it's already been handled, then we break, so we stop dispatching
我们停止将其传播到更多层，对于KeyPressedEvent，就像我们不在乎可以影响一切一样
and we stop propagating it to further layers um with KeyPressedEvent, like we don't care can affect everything
当我们不想阻止和使用输入时，在这种情况下返回true或false都无关紧要
when we don't want to block and consume the input, um it doesn't matter if you return true or false in this case
因为我们没有任何其他层来阻止按键事件
because we don't have any other layers where key events are gonna be blocked
我认为ImGui自己会处理，所以无论如何它都不会阻止它
um I think ImGui does his own handling, so it's not gonna block it from that anyway
但假设我们有一个类似的用户界面层，当你们输入用户界面层时，你们知道你们不想要这个
um but if suppose we did have like a UI layers, and when you type in the UI layers, you know like you don't want um
你们知道，因为你们的用户界面中有一个类似文本字段的内容，所以你们不希望字符移动
you know, because you have like a text field in your UI, you don't want the character to move
如果你们使用，如果你们键入WASD键，因为你们正在输入文本
if you use the, if you type the WASD keys, because you're entering text
在这一点上，你们返回true，当你们知道，当你们想要阻止它时
that's at which point you return true, when you know, when you want to block that
让我们来看看这个，所以如果event.GetKeyCode()==HZ_KEY_LEFT，会向左移动，对吧
um okay, so let's check this out, so if event.GetKeyCode() is HZ_KEY_LEFT I guess, we'll move left, right
所以我们要做的就是我们有这个相机，很棒，但实际上会有glm::vec3 m_CameraPosition
so the way that we'll do that is we have this camera, which is great, but I'm actually going to have a glm::vec3 m_CameraPosition
好了，我们从构造函数内部的m_CameraPosition开始，就是0，对吧
okay, and we're gonna start off this camera position over here inside the constructor as being just zero, right
所以我想我不知道我们能不能像那样写0，我们能不能，我想我们不能
so I think I don't know if we can supply 0 like that, can we actually, I don't think we can
让我们看看那样是否会编译
let's see if that even compiles
因为我认为我们需要具体地使用三个，或者可能不使用，也许那会起作用
because I think that we need to specifically use three or maybe not maybe that will work yeah
好了，很好，它应该可以，所以有一个构造函数，只需要一个缩放
okay, good, yeah it should, um so that there's a constructor, that just takes a scaler
所以在这种情况下，对吧，我们想要获取那个cameraPosition，我们想要把它向左移动
um so in this case, right, we want to take that camera position, and we want to move it left
好了，我们将相机向左移动，所以为了实现那个，我们只需说x-=某一速度
right, we're moving the camera left, so to do that, we just say dot x minus equals a certain speed
所以就是m_CameraSpeed，好了，这将是我们在这里定义的浮点数
so m_CameraSpeed will see, okay, and this will be a float that we define here for example
所以就是float m_CameraSpeed，我们开始的时候大概是0.1左右，这可能太快了
so float m_CameraSpeed, we're gonna start it off as being like 0.1 or something, which is probably gonna be too fast
现在，我的意思是这里有一个很大的问题，对吧
now at the moment, I mean there's a huge problem here, right
因为如果我的意思是每一帧都有事件被调度，对吧
because if I mean events get dispatched every frame, right
这在某种程度上取决于我们的实际移动速度、实际渲染帧速率，或者应用运行的速度
this is gonna be kind of dependent on our actual speed of movement, our actual rendering frame rate, or how fast our application runs
我们确实想要使用DeltaTime，很可能我不会真的，就像你们可能不想把它作为事件来做
we do want to use something called delta time, and most likely I would not really, like you might not want to do this as an event
你们可能只想通过轮询在OnUpdate中这样做，对吧，我也可以向你们展示如何实现那个
you might want to just do this like in the OnUpdate function via polling, right, and I can show you guys how to do that as well
但是要正确实现那个，我们需要实际找出我们的应用的运行速度，并计算DeltaTime
but to do that properly, we'll need to actually find out how fast our application is running, and calculate something called DeltaTime
因此，我们实际上移动了相机，而不考虑应用的实际运行速度
so that we actually moved the camera independent of how fast our application is actually running
当然即使打开了v-sync，意味着应用的运行速度是每秒60帧或每秒60次更新
because of course even if we have v-sync turned on, which would mean that this app is running as 60 frames per second or 60 updates per second
例如有人有个144Hz的监视器，以每秒144次的速度运行，除非它看起来不能那么快地渲染
someone has a 144 hertz monitor for example, it will run at 144 times per second unless it's like not able to render that quickly
所以在这种情况下，相机会移动得更快，所以那是需要考虑的事情，我们以后会这样做
so in which case the camera will move faster, so that's stuff to think about that, we'll do in the future
但现在，非常简单的事情，我们先做左右方向键
but for now, really easy stuff, we'll do KeyLeft, we'll do KeyRight
这基本上使我们的相机位置增加了空间，所以我们向右移动，然后上下移动也会这样做
which basically increments our camera position right by the space, so we move right and then up and down is going to do the same to
为什么，所以如果我们向下移动，我们想要将相机向下移动，所以是负数
why, so if we move down, we want to move the camera down, so negative
然后如果我们按向上箭头，我们想要向上移动它
and then if we press the up arrow, we want to move it up
最后，在我们做这些事情之前，我们想要做的是在OnUpdate内部
and then finally what we want to do is inside OnUpdate, before we do this stuff
我们希望将相机的位置设置为m_CameraPosition，好了，我们暂时还不会考虑旋转
we want to set our camera's position to be in camera position, okay, we won't worry about rotation yet
我把它保留为0，让我们点击f5，看看会发生什么，好了，这是我们的应用，如果按左或右
I'll just leave that at zero, let's hit at f5 and see what happens, okay, so here is our app, and if I press left or right
你们可以看到它在移动，现在这是个KeyPressedEvent
you can see it moves, now this is a KeyPressedEvent
正如你们所看到的，它只在按键被按下时才做出反应
and as you can see, it's only reacting, when the key is actually pressed
然后重复，对吧，所以我们得到了这种非常笨重的移动，根本不是我们想要的
and then repeated, right, so we get this kind of really chunky movement, it's not really what we want at all
因为它是一个事件系统，对吧，它对按键做出反应，这意味着我可以像这样
because it's an event system, right, it reacts to key presses, it means that I can just be like blah blah blah blah
就像我在这里按向左，对吧，我不知道这些奇怪的声音是怎么回事
like I'm pressing left here, right, doom doom doom doom doom, and I don't know what's up with these weird noises
我正在制造。。。但不管怎样，它移动了我的实际相机那么多，这是很棒的
I'm making weather way, but anyway, it's moving my actual camera that amount, which is great
如果你们想浏览菜单，这个东西非常适合
this stuff is great for like, if you want to navigate through a menu
但如果你们真的想要流畅，比如引擎游戏或其他什么
but if you actually want smooth in like in engine gameplay or whatever
你们想要正确地移动你们的角色或相机，这些东西都是垃圾
and you want to actually move your character or your camera properly, this stuff is rubbish
因此，让我们继续，不使用事件系统
so let's go ahead and not use an event system
而是使用，并按照你们应该使用的方式使用OnUpdate函数
and use, and use out OnUpdate function like you're supposed to
好了，让我们进入OnUpdate，而不是做所有这些
okay, so let's go over here into OnUpdate, and instead of doing all of this
所有这些东西，那么就是if (Input::IsKeyPressed(HZ_KEY_UP))
all of this stuff, we just want to say if input::IsKeyDown or IsKeyPressed HZ_KEY_UP or whatever
事实上，我只是想复制这些东西，因为它会很愚蠢
in fact I'm just gonna copy this stuff, because it's gonna be stupid
因此不再是event.GetKeyCode()，而是Input::IsKeyPressed，当然这是Hazel::Input
so instead of writing event.GetKeyCode(), we instead do IsKeyPressed just like that, of course this is Hazel::Input
所以可以复制它，把它放在这里的任何地方，对吧，那么应该发生什么，显然会删掉这些
so we can copy this and put it all everywhere over here, right, so now what should happen, and will obviously get rid of all of this stuff
事实上，我会完全去掉它，因为我们现在不需要它，我想保持这个代码的干净
and in fact I'll get rid of this completely, because we don't need it right now, and I want to keep this code pretty clean um
我们现在要做的就是点击f5键，现在在更新循环中，每次更新，只要按下左键就可以进行
what we're going to do now is just hit f5, and now in the update loop, whenever we like if the left keys pressed every single update
它实际上会移动我们的相机，所以这应该是完全丝滑的
it will actually move our camera, so this should be completely smooth
这就是你们从一个真正的游戏中期待的东西
and this is the kind of stuff that you would expect from an actual game
所以你们可以看到，当我现在移动的时候，它就会移动，这很棒
so as you can see, when I move right now, it moves, which is awesome
现在，如果你们有一个更高频刷新监视器，它可能会移动得很快，以至直接移出屏幕
now if you have a higher fresh ray monitor, it might move, so quickly that it just moves off the screen
对吧，如果你们打开了v-sync，如果你们关闭了v-sync，那么就像RIP
right, if you've got v-sync turned on, um if you have beating turned off, then like rip
好了，这将使它以每秒1000或2000 4000兰特的速度运行，而你们根本看不到这个
right, this is gonna just run it up 1000 or 2000 4000 rans per second, and you're not gonna see this at all
但你们每秒可以看到它60次，这还不错，好吧，就那样，我们可以移动相机
but you can see it 60 times per second, this isn't bad, okay, so that's it, we can move our camera
让我们看看我们是否也能旋转我们的相机，所以我要做的就是说
um let's see if we can rotate our camera as well, so what I'll do is I'll just say that
如果我们有，顺便说一句，你们可能应该做的是，对于上下可能需要elif
if we have, oh and by the way, what you probably should do is, like an elseif or something for up and down
否则，你们实际上可能会取消彼此的动作，所以我会说，else if
otherwise you can actually end up canceling each other's like movement, so I'll say that we'll say else if
如果我们这样做，这意味着这个键优先于这个键，这通常是好了
and if we do that, it means that this key has precedence over this key, which is usually fine
我可能会说向上优先于向下，所以向上移动，向上，好了，酷，就这样
I might say up has precedence over down though, so up moves it, up, okay, cool, so there we go
所以如果我可以说，如果按下a键，对吧，我们可能会说旋转，相机旋转，这是我没有的
so if I might say, if the a key is pressed, right, we might say that the rotation, camera rotation, which I don't have
让我们创建一个称为m_CameraRotation的浮点数，我们会将其设置为0
let's make a float called m_CameraRotation, we'll set that equal to zero
如果我们按下a键，我想就是m_CameraRotation -= m_CameraSpeed
um if uh we press the a key camera rotation minus equals camera speed I guess
你们可能应该把这个拆分一下，有一个相机的旋转速度，所以我们会看到相机的移动速度
um you should probably break this up, and have like a camera rotation speed, so we'll see camera move speed
使用Alt+Shift+r调出VA重构这个
although factor this alt shift r with visual assist camera move
我该怎么做，应该是cameraMoveSpeed，而不是cameraMoveRotation，cameraMoveSpeed
well what do I do, cameraMoveSpeed not cameraMoveRotation, cameraMoveSpeed
然后是cameraRotation，然后是cameraRotationSpeed，好了
and then cameraRotation, and then cameraRotationSpeed, okay
哎呀，我不知道我是怎么做到的，这显然就是那样，我会为这个做0.1
whoops I don't know how I did that, this is obviously just gonna be that, and I'll do 0.1 for this
这样我们就可以有一个独立的移动和旋转速度
so that way we can have an independent speed for movement and for rotation
所以我们会看到m_CameraRotation -= m_CameraRotationSpeed
so we'll see cameraRotation minus equals cameraRotationSpeed
然后至于d键，我们会看到它正向旋转
and then with the d key, we'll see that it rotates in a positive direction
好了，让我们看看我们得到了什么，好了，所以a和d绝对不做任何事情
okay, so let's see what we get here, alright, so a and d do absolutely nothing
因为我忘了把相机的旋转插入到我们的旋转中
because of course I forgot to actually plug in camera rotation into our rotation
我们仍在将旋转设置为0，所以让我们正确地这样做，然后看看会发生什么
we're still setting our rotation to zero, so let's just do that properly, and then see what happens
好了，我们开始了，所以a和d旋转相机，虽然很慢，因为它不是，我想它是以度为单位的
alright, there we go, so that a and d rotate the camera, that's very slow though, because it isn't, I guess it is in degrees
所以我们可能想把它改成2.0之类的
so we probably want to change this more to like tube or something like that
而且你们可以看到，你们可能会看到它实际上是朝着另一个方向旋转的
um and furthermore you can see that, you might see that it's actually rotating it the other way
所以当我减去等于cameraRotationSpeed，它实际上是在旋转
um so when I do minus equals cameraRotationSpeed, um it's actually rotating
这看起来就像是我在旋转物体而不是相机，因为它应该朝另一个方向移动，不是吗
it almost looks like I'm rotating the object instead of the camera, because it should be going the other way, shouldn't it
那是因为正旋转实际上是向右旋转，而负旋转是顺时针旋转
um that's because a positive rotation actually rotates this way right, and a negative rotation rotates clockwise
那就是它的运行方式，因此，如果按下a，你们实际上想做一个+=cameraRotationSpeed
that's just the way that it works, so because of that, you actually want to do a plus equals to the cameraRotationSpeed, if we press a
如果我们想要旋转，我们想要将相机向左旋转
and if we wanted to rotate kind of, we wanted to rotate the camera left
然后减去，如果我们按下d键，就像负旋转一样
and then minus equals door do like a negative rotation, if we press the d key
我们来解决这个问题，然后按f5键，我们应该做对了，对吧
so let's fix that and press f5, and we should get this right,
所以现在我基本上可以移动我的相机了，对吧，我可以旋转我的相机了
so now I can basically move my camera, right, and I can rotate my camera
那一切都和你们预期的一样，好吧，现在我们有了一个移动的东西，很难说
and that all works as you would expect, okay, so now we have a moving thing, it's kind of hard to tell
因为我们只渲染了一个，对我们来说很容易改变它或等待，它不是
because we're just rendering one thing, pretty easy for us to change it or wait, it's not
因为目前我们渲染事物的方式只是通过我们的顶点位置
because at the moment the way that we render things is only by our vertex positions
所以我们实际上需要做的是能够在不同的位置渲染对象，对吧
so what we actually need to do is be able to render objects in different positions, right
我们现在不能这样做，当我们提交一些东西时，就像是一个带有烘焙顶点的顶点数组
which we can't do right now, when we submit something, that's it, it's just like a vertex array with his baked vertices
然后是着色器，我们没有办法说我希望这个对象有这个变换
and then a shader, we have no way of saying I want this object to have this transform
那就是我们需要做的事情，我们可能会下期做，另一种选择是
and so that's something that we need to do, we might do that next episode, the other alternative is
正如我现在所说的，这些东西实际上就是我们的应用程序实际更新的速度
this stuff as I said right now is bound to actually just be the speed at which our application is actually updating
我们希望这个独立于那个
we want this to be independent of that
所以我们需要引入一种叫做增量时间的东西，基本上做适当的时间类型的步骤管理
so we need to introduce something called delta time and basically do proper time kind of step management
所以那就是我们所能做的另一个选择，我们下一次可能会做这两个中的一个
so that's another option of what we what we can do, we'll probably do one of those two next time
我想我只是想把DeltaTime去掉，因为那是你们知道的，我们应该很早就知道
I think I just want to get delta time out of the way, because that's something that you know, we should have pretty early on
这将使我们能够修复所有关于代码的东西，并使其真正为你们所有人正确运行
and it will just enable us to fix all about code kind of, and make it actually run for all of you guys properly
无论如何，希望你们喜欢这个视频，如果你们喜欢的话，就为它点赞吧
anyway, hope you guys enjoyed this video, if you did, hit the like button
你们也可以通过访问patreon.com/theCherno来帮助支持该系列
you can also help support the series by going over to patreon.com/TheCherno
在那里你们会提前得到下期视频，并可以访问我提到的Hazel开发分支
where you'll get episodes early and access to the Hazel development branch as I mentioned
所以我们有两个问题，我今天想在这里做的两件事
so we have kind of two issues, two things that I want to do here today
我们设法从Application类中移除了一切
we managed to kind of get everything out of the Application class
我们的Application类现在实际上是干净的，让我们回到Application类
our Application class is actually clean now actually, let's go back to the Application class
因为我认为不，不，我确实这样做了，我以为我忘了从头文件中删除内容
because I think that no, no, I actually did, I thought that I forgot to remove stuff from the header file
但不，我们在这里做得很好，我们实际上可以去掉这个HazelAPI，我们不再需要它了
but no, we're pretty good here, we can actually get rid of this HazelAPI, we don't need that anymore
这个东西包含几乎所有的东西，着色器、缓冲区和顶点数组
this stuff includes almost everything, um yeah shader of buffer about vertex array
那就是我所说的东西，我们不再需要那些包含了
that's the stuff I was talking about, um we don't need any of those includes anymore
如果你们不再需要你们的内容，清理它们是很重要的，因为有些东西人们经常会忘记
it's important to clean up your includes, if you don't need them anymore, because there's something that people often forget
但是你们可以看到我们的Application类非常好而且干净，只有79行
um but you can see that our Application class is really nice and clean again, like 79 lines occurred
很漂亮，我们的SandboxApp实际上什么都有
beautiful, and our SandboxApp actually has everything
这很好，因为这实际上是我们使用Hazel引擎实际渲染的一个例子
so that's good, because it's actually an example of us using Hazel engine to actually render something
甚至还添加了交互功能，这非常酷
and even add interaction to it, which is pretty cool
好了，所以下期，我们可能会看看增量时间，它是如何运行，以及为什么一开始就需要它
okay, so next time, we're probably gonna take a look at delta time, and how that works, and why we need it even in the first place
那应该会很有趣，所以我们下期再见，拜
and that should be a lot of fun, so I'll see you guys in next episode, goodbye